<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="86" moduleid="5865" modulename="book" contextid="19726">
  <book id="86">
    <name>Session 2: Access and Use of One-Stops</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;part 2 of guiding question #2&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1457394151</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1460389733</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="701">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Resources to help locate the nearest One-Stop</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Resources to help locate the nearest One-Stop&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As stated previously, the best resource for locating your nearest one-stop is &lt;a href="http://www.careeronestop.org/localhelp/local-help.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;careeronestop.org&lt;/a&gt;. These links provide a quick and easy online search tool, resulting in information about services and procedures, phone contacts, addresses, maps and directions. In addition, these sites provide nationwide toll-free contact numbers for accessing jobs services, and accessing help in using the web sites. Adult learners and instructors can contact the AJC to ask about their hours, range of services, programs, and points-of-contact for serving individuals with disabilities, as well as explore existing or potential partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Screen%20Shot%202016-03-07%20at%206.46.05%20PM.png" width="526" height="540" alt="Screenshot of careeronestop.org." style="border: 1px solid black;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468534062</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="702">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Locate your One-Stop and consider barriers to accessing services</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Locate your One-Stop and consider barriers to accessing services&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have not already done so, please take a few minutes to locate your local one-stop via &lt;a href="http://www.careeronestop.org/localhelp/local-help.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;careeronestop.org&lt;/a&gt;. Once you have located it, review the description of resources and services, as well as the location and hours for this center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then take a moment to consider and write down your answer to the following question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ___________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;"&gt;What barriers might your learners might face in accessing services via this one-stop?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; ___________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have located your local one-stop and generated a list of two or more barriers, click the &lt;strong&gt;forward arrow&lt;/strong&gt; for some ideas to overcome these and other barriers.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468534127</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="703">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Registration and orientation</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Registration and orientation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because everyone has different career needs, a job seeker may or may not meet all of the staff working in the one-stop. Every job seeker should, however, come in contact with staff at the front desk and in the career resource room or area. The front desk staff are responsible for welcoming people to the center and directing them to the proper personnel or service. Many centers provide an orientation that describes their services in a group setting or have someone who will meet with the job seeker one-on-one. Because services vary from center to center, it is very valuable for the job seeker to visit his or her nearest one-stop in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Clipboard_bullet1.jpg" width="395" height="466" alt="A piece of paper on a clipboard with “Accessing and Using Your Local One-Stop” typed at the top of the page and one bullet underneath labeled “Registration and orientation.”" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463433057</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="704">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Staffed resource room/area</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Staffed resource room/area&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the first visit, the job seeker is typically directed to the resource room or area. The resource rooms usually have computers with internet access, accessible workstations, a copier, a fax machine, telephones, TTY (or Text Telephone), a career resource library and literature about partners and community services. Trained staff are on hand to help the job seeker access the state’s database. This online system allows individuals to enter their skills and interest areas, and employers to list their vacancies and to search for candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Clipboard_bullets2.jpg" width="395" height="466" alt="A piece of paper on a clipboard with “Accessing and Using Your Local One-Stop” typed at the top of the page and two bullets underneath labeled “Registration and Orientation” and “Staffed resource room/area.”" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463433108</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="705">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Assistive technology</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Assistive technology&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Centers offer assistive technology for people with disabilities, such as TTYs for people who are deaf or hard of hearing, accessible workstations for people who use wheelchairs, word prediction software, computer magnification or screen reader software, sign language interpreters upon request and personnel who specialize in working with veterans, youth, seniors, and/or people who speak languages other than English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Clipboard_bullets3.jpg" width="395" height="466" alt="A piece of paper on a clipboard with “Accessing and Using Your Local One-Stop” typed at the top of the page and three bullets underneath labeled “Registration and Orientation, Staffed resource room/area, and Assistive technology.”" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463433173</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="706">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Supporting learners to access and use the One-Stops</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Supporting learners to access and use the One-Stops&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The many resources and services provided by the one-stops can be extremely valuable to ABE learners with LD as they pursue their employment goals. However, they may need some assistance in learning how to access and fully utilize those services. Let’s explore how you would help a learner prepare to visit a one stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, think of a learner you know who may benefit from accessing a one-stop. Write that learner’s name on a blank piece of paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, record some ideas on what you could do in your current role to support this learner in accessing and using their nearest one-stop career center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have completed your reflections, click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; for some ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1460389912</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="707">
        <pagenum>7</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Ideas for supporting learners to access and use the One-Stop</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Ideas for supporting learners to access and use the One-stop&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You probably came up with a number of ideas for supporting your learner. Here are a few ideas to compare with your own and/or for additional consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To support and encourage a learner to access and use their one-stop career center you could:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arrange a class field visit to the one-stop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage students to explore their state’s Department of Labor web sites before visiting the one-stop to get a sense of what to expect. Many offer stand-alone online services that are directly connected to the one-stop. The instructor might give an assignment related to that research, asking the student to present key information uncovered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If possible, prior to the orientation, encourage the learner to speak with the orientation facilitator a few days in advance, in order to get a sense of the key concepts that will be covered.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support a student who struggles socially to go to the one-stop with a friend - the two of them can register for core services together. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457469327</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="708">
        <pagenum>8</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Share your thoughts and ideas in the discussion forum</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Share your thoughts and ideas in the discussion forum&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this topic we discussed one-stop partners, customers and services, and we explored some ideas for assisting students with LD to access these services effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a few moments to consider the information and ideas presented. Then answer the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have you used the services of your local one-stop?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which services seem to be the most effective in helping your students?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you have any ideas, other than those presented, for assisting learners with LD in accessing one-stop services?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please share your reflections and ideas, and read other teachers’ responses in the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/discussion/online-course-learning-achieve-workforce-preparation-strategies" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Disabilities in Adult Education Group&lt;/a&gt; before moving on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #993300;"&gt;When you have finished posting your ideas, continue on to the Conclusion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457469350</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>