<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="85" moduleid="5864" modulename="book" contextid="19725">
  <book id="85">
    <name>Session 1: One-Stops</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;one-stops&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1457389756</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1460389720</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="688">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>One-Stops/American Job Centers</title>
        <content>&lt;h1&gt;One-Stops/American Job Centers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the primary employment-related resources available to adult learners with LD is the workforce system’s American Job Centers (AJCs), also known as one-stops. There are a number of ways ABE instructors can tie materials and services of the one-stops to their instructional strategies to help the learner with LD meet both his/her educational and occupational goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All adult education instructors should be familiar with the location and services of their local &lt;a href="http://www.careeronestop.org/localhelp/local-help.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;one-stop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s examine the elements of the one-stops and how they are linked to both adult basic education and to all of the concepts previously discussed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/OneStop_V1.png" width="277" height="182" alt="CAreer one-stop logo with the tagline &amp;quot;pathways to career success&amp;quot;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468533132</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="689">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (WIOA)</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (WIOA)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (WIOA) updates the membership and required functions for local workforce investment boards (LWIBs), which were also required under the previous Workforce Investment Act (WIA). See section 107 of WIOA for the membership requirements and required functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WIOA authorizes &lt;a href="https://www.dol.gov/general/topic/training/onestop" target="_blank"&gt;one-stop career centers&lt;/a&gt; to provide an array of employment services and connects customers to work-related training and education. WIOA places greater emphasis on the one-stops to achieve results for jobseekers, workers, and businesses through enhanced partnerships. The U.S. Department of Labor has also released a &lt;a href="https://www.doleta.gov/wioa/Docs/WIOA_OneStop_FactSheet.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;fact sheet&lt;/a&gt; that summarizes the changes enacted by WIOA to the one-stop system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every local area is required to have a one-stop where a variety of employment-related resources are made available to the public, which includes job seekers, those who assist them and employers. Essentially, the one-stop is an employment hub—a physical location where patrons can work at their own pace with job search and career planning tools and resources geared toward finding employment. The users of the one-stops are very diverse and reflect the citizens of the communities in which they are located.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468533209</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="690">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>WIOA nondiscrimination and equal opportunity regulations</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;WIOA nondiscrimination and equal opportunity regulations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One-stops must be universally accessible, meaning that any individual can access the core services of the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nondiscrimination and equal opportunity regulations for WIOA are very clear. People with disabilities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have a right to use the services of the one-stop network;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;are entitled to reasonable accommodations and modifications when using one-stop services; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;should not be automatically referred to agencies that serve only people with disabilities, including the public vocational rehabilitation system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can locate the nearest one-stop by visiting &lt;a href="http://www.careeronestop.org/localhelp/local-help.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.careeronestop.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at the various components of a one-stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/146953707.jpg" width="600" height="400" alt="Disabled logo painted on pavers." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468533286</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="691">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>One-Stop partner agencies</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;One-Stop partner agencies&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the significant strengths of the one-stop concept is that diverse partner agencies are able to work together, offering seamless services to job seekers and delivering services more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many components to one-stops, including specifics regarding partners, customers, and services. We’ll examine each of these areas in more detail as part of our answer to guiding question number two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1460389786</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="692">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>One-Stop partners</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;One-Stop partners&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One-stop partners must include the following core programs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WIOA Title I (Adult, Dislocated Worker, and Youth formula programs) administered by Department of Labor;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adult Education and Family Literacy Act programs administered by the Department of Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wagner-Peyser Act employment services administered by the Department of Labor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rehabilitation Act Title I programs administered by the Department of Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a full list of services that are required to be available through the one-stop, see the &lt;a href="https://www.doleta.gov/wioa/Docs/WIOA_OneStop_FactSheet.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;DOL Fact Sheet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those supporting adults with LD, it is important to note that adult education and vocational rehabilitation are &lt;i&gt;mandated&lt;/i&gt; partners. In some one-stops, staff members from these agencies are located onsite.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1460389799</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="693">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Public vocational rehabilitation system – a mandated partner</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Public vocational rehabilitation system – a mandated partner&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, supports are available for qualified job seekers with disabilities, including LD. The most well known provider of these services is the public vocational rehabilitation system – also known as ‘Voc Rehab’ or VR. Depending on your location, Community Rehabilitation Providers (CRPs), or other public disability agencies may also provide valuable services to adults with LD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The public Vocational Rehabilitation (VR) system is one of many mandated partners in the one-stop network, with VR services available to at least some degree via the one-stop system. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457391839</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="694">
        <pagenum>7</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Vocational rehabilitation services</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Vocational rehabilitation services&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifics on how these services are delivered vary from state to state (this includes both general VR services and services for the blind and visually impaired, which are part of the public VR system). For example, in some cases the entire local office of VR is located at a one-stop, while in other cases, individual VR counselors are based at a one-stop on a full-time or part-time basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vocational rehabilitation services can include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;diagnosis of disabilities;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;evaluation of job skills;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;psychological evaluation;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;career counseling;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;assistance in looking for work;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;job search classes;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;asssistive technology (e.g., computer software, reading machines and tape recorders);&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;social skills classes;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;job coaches; and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;payment of tuition fees.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468533633</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="695">
        <pagenum>8</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Community Rehabilitation Providers</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Community Rehabilitation Providers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Community Rehabilitation Providers (CRPs) are local agencies that are often contractors to the state VR system, which pays them to provide employment-related services for job seekers with disabilities. Typically these agencies serve specific disability categories, such as visual impairments, intellectual disabilities or LD. CRPs are not mandated partners; however, local one-stops may choose to include these agencies in their list of voluntary partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/IND_083sm.jpg" width="358" height="537" alt="Photo of woman working with a machine shop drill while a man observes." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457392001</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="696">
        <pagenum>9</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>VR system integral, but separate</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;VR system integral, but separate&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While under WIA each state's public VR system must be an integral component of the workforce investment system, VR continues to exist as a separate program, with its own federal funding source and eligibility requirements. The VR system is the only &lt;i&gt;disability-focused agency &lt;/i&gt;that is a required partner in the one-stop system under WIOA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/OneStops_VRsCombo.jpg" width="548" height="365" alt="Photo of a woman at a desk showing another woman a form. as well as an organizational chart graphic showing the AJCs box with a double-sided arrow pointing to the Vocational Rehabilitation box." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457393304</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="697">
        <pagenum>10</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Other disability-related partners</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Other disability-related partners&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note, however, that states and local areas can have additional partners in the one-stop system, which may include public disability agencies such as state or county mental health agencies and state developmental disability agencies. These agencies, in turn, may or may not partner with each other.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457393321</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="698">
        <pagenum>11</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Disability self-disclosure requirement</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Disability self-disclosure requirement&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that in order to access these specialized supports, students with LD must disclose their disability. More information on self-disclosure can be found in the &lt;a href="https://courses.lincs.ed.gov/1/" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Self-Determination course&lt;/a&gt; of the Learning to Achieve online learning series.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457393386</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="699">
        <pagenum>12</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Individuals who serve as guides for One-Stops</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Individuals who serve as guides for One-Stops&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One-stops can serve as a valuable resource for job seekers with disabilities, including those with LD. However, that local career centers do not all offer the same services. Job seekers with disabilities need to be aware that one-stops may have an individual (or individuals) to help in this process. Because these individuals’ titles vary depending on location, job seekers with a disability may be referred to (or need to ask for):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AJC liaisons;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;points of contact;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;guides; and/or&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;a resources person.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These individuals can guide the job seeker with a disability in taking full advantage of the services, programs, and resources provided by the center. It can be extremely useful to have a point of contact who is very familiar with accommodations and knowledgeable about the array of specialized services offered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we will look at who the AJCs serve.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468533940</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="700">
        <pagenum>13</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Business services team</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Business services team&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engaging employers in the one-stop network is a critical part of the equation. These are the people who offer job opportunities. Typically a business services team in every one-stop actively engages the business community in identifying the services they need and assists them in meeting those needs. For example, they will help companies list their job openings on the state’s database at no cost to the business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Businesses can also&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;search for qualified candidates registered within the system, and matches can be found online. For more direct hiring, the business services team might host recruitment events for businesses at the one-stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other business services may include targeted job fairs, candidate searches, trainings, assistance with layoffs, relocations and much more. With the assistance of agency representatives and educators, these vital business services often result in job offers on the spot for active job seekers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #993300;"&gt;Continue on to Session 2: Access and Use of One-stops&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457472820</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>