<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="83" moduleid="5862" modulename="book" contextid="19723">
  <book id="83">
    <name>Session 2: Career Development</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;part 2 of 2 in guiding question #1&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1456962986</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1460390708</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="662">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>The role of ABE instructors in the Career Development Process</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;The role of ABE instructors in the Career Development Process&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although ABE instructors are not expected to provide career counseling and education, they do play an important role in helping students see the connection between their academic efforts and the critical components of successful work. In addition, many career-related materials and resources can serve as content for academic instruction. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457033259</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="663">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Career Development Process overview</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Career Development Process overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Career development can most easily be explained as having four major components or stages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;awareness of self;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;awareness of opportunity;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;preparation; and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;work history.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not considered a linear process; rather, individuals are constantly moving back and forth through the various stages throughout their lives. Career development encompasses many life experiences, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;education and training;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;avocations;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;everyday tasks; and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;work experiences (paid or unpaid).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, career development is a lifelong process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468528203</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="664">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Awareness of self</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Awareness of self&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the first important component of career development – &lt;b&gt;awareness of self&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking stock of one’s attributes and abilities is one of the most important steps in determining the types of endeavors an individual would like to pursue – that is, the types of activities, circumstances, education, training and employment that would be a good match for that person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to academic skills, there are many other categories of skills, such as physical/manual, artistic, technical, mechanical, people and so forth. ABE instructors can play an important role in directing students (and certainly those with LD) to counseling resources where they can be given—with accommodations if needed—career interest and aptitude assessments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Awareness of self example&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Feedback"&gt;For example, John Holland’s Self-Directed Search is one such instrument, highly regarded and widely used. It can be completed online. Another example is the Strong Interest Inventory assessment which measures career and leisure interests. This assessment is often used to help people in making education and career decisions. Other useful resources are the inventories that can be found on the Career Counseling Resources page at EducationWorld. Visit the Course Resources page at the end of this course to explore these career interest and aptitude assessments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This component of career development is also one of the key factors that is linked with an individual’s ability to be self-determined. More information on self-determination can be found in the &lt;a href="https://ovae-moodle-dev.myquotient.net/course/view.php?id=87" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Self-Determination course&lt;/a&gt; of the Learning to Achieve online learning series.&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; when you are ready to move on to the second important component of career development.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462811150</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="665">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Awareness of opportunity</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Awareness of opportunity&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next component of Career Development is awareness of opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is not uncommon for people to experience difficulty determining the kind of career that would be best for them. In order to pursue a job, one must first be aware that an opportunity exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, exposure to the many different types of jobs available, and exploration of various job tasks and responsibilities, are key career development activities. Determining a ‘good fit’ is particularly important to the individual with a learning disability. Matching one’s career to the individual’s areas of strength and interest is a key predictor of success and job satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that awareness of opportunities for advancement once employed and how to seek out those opportunities are additional skills that may require development for the individual with a learning disability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/124135652.jpg" width="600" height="450" alt="Image of the help wanted section of a newspaper with a figure of a person standing in the middle and arrows going in different directions." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457049625</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="666">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Preparation</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Preparation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does an individual prepare for employment and/or prepare for advancement once employed?  Some people “fall into” a job. An opportunity becomes available for which they have the skills, and without much thought, they are hired  and receive on-the-job training. In this case, preparation is very basic. However, this is exceedingly rare; the vast majority of jobs require more formal preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ABE instructor can direct students to research the types of education and training that are required for different occupations of interest. Job search skills also fall under this category. Finding job leads, preparing resumes, completing applications, effectively interviewing and following up with prospective employers are concrete skills that may require direct instruction. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457033647</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="667">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Work readiness</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Work readiness&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 class="Subhead"&gt;Work readiness falls under Career Development Process components awareness of opportunity and preparation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Note that the concept of work readiness, which includes employability skills, falls under the career development components of “awareness of opportunity” and “preparation.” On this topic there are many excellent resources and materials for instructors and students that integrate basic skills and either ‘work readiness’ or ‘employability’ skills.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At your leisure (using the search engine of your choice), search for the following terms and explore several of the resources available:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work readiness&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work readiness skills&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employability skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American Job Centers (AJCs) or one-stop career centers, which we will be discussing later in this course, are also a good source for work readiness assessments and resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Work%20Readiness-CDP.jpg" width="400" height="191" alt="The diagram depicts the relationship of work readiness and employability skills to the Career Develop Process components of awareness of opportunity and preparation. Awareness of opportunity and preparation are part of work readiness and employability skills in general." style="vertical-align: middle;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Label"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457468905</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="668">
        <pagenum>7</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Accommodations Resources</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Accommodations Resources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While exploring job opportunities and preparing for employment, adults with LD need to consider issues surrounding any accommodations they might need to perform job tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One online resource that you can recommend to your learners is the Job Accommodations Network (JAN). &lt;a href="http://askjan.org/"&gt;AskJAN.org&lt;/a&gt; is designed to provide employers, people with disabilities, their family members, service providers, educators, and others with technical assistance on job accommodations and the Americans with Disabilities Act. For job seekers, this resource includes accommodation ideas, information on your rights, and supports for finding jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on accommodations can be found in both the &lt;a href="https://courses.lincs.ed.gov/1/enrol/index.php?id=3" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Accommodations course&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://courses.lincs.ed.gov/1/"&gt;Legal Issues, Self-Disclosure, and Confidentiality course&lt;/a&gt; of the Learning to Achieve online course series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let’s talk about the last component of CDP – work history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt; &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Screen%20Shot%202016-03-03%20at%202.43.25%20PM.png" width="517" height="395" alt="Screenshot from the askJAN.org website." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468530394</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="669">
        <pagenum>8</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Work history</title>
        <content>&lt;h1&gt;Work history&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to emphasize to ABE/GED students the value of every job they have ever held, regardless of whether they liked it or were successful in that job. It is important to gather every possible experience and skill that can become part of a comprehensive picture of one’s strengths and abilities. Then, once employed in a new position, it is important to keep a log of employment experiences and skills acquired on the job that can be transferred to new opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Career Development Process component links to the key factor of valuing oneself as discussed in the &lt;a href="https://courses.lincs.ed.gov/1/"&gt;LINCS Self-Determination course&lt;/a&gt; of the Learning to Achieve online course series. You may wish to complete that course to learn more about this topic.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457034622</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="670">
        <pagenum>9</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Application of the four Career Development Process components</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Application of the four Career Development Process components&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These four components: awareness of self, awareness of opportunity, preparation, and work history, apply to everyone, regardless of life circumstances. They apply to every type of occupation, and every level—from unskilled, entry-level work to skilled jobs to highly professional positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s think about possible activities that can reinforce the notion of &lt;i&gt;career components &lt;/i&gt;and how these components can be incorporated into ABE lessons.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457050637</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="671">
        <pagenum>10</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Identify instructional activities for supporting Career Development Process components</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Identify instructional activities for supporting Career Development Process components&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about a learner you know who is struggling with employment. Write his or her name on a piece of paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which Career Development Process component would you focus on and how? Remember, the four components are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;awareness of self;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;awareness of opportunity;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;preparation; and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;work history.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a few moments to write down the component and list a few ways you plan to address the component with the learner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have completed the activity, click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; for some ideas you might want to consider.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468530479</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="672">
        <pagenum>11</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Awareness of self: example instructional activities</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Awareness of self: example instructional activities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For awareness of self, example activities include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make an inventory of the learner’s skill and career interest areas, incorporating any relevant findings from assessments in which they may have participated.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ABE instructor can direct adult learners to career guidance services that can provide assessments and give advice for career exploration. Examples include American Job Centers (AJCs) or vocational rehabilitation (VR). Both of these important resources will be covered later in this course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/87539590.jpg" width="600" height="400" alt="Photo of a female instructor helping a young adult male student with a writing assignment." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457468946</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="673">
        <pagenum>12</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Awareness of opportunity: example instructional activities</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Awareness of opportunity: example instructional activities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;awareness of opportunity, example activities include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ABE instructor can emphasize how important it is for students to discover all they can about career possibilities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can research local companies online, through phone calls, or by visiting the companies.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can also interview people who work in different fields to gain insights and advice about occupational possibilities. They will be able to learn how people got certain jobs, what education and training they received, etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students should keep a record of these experiences in a journal.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In addition, many local libraries have career exploration resources.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learners interested in exploring military service can take the Armed Services Vocational Aptitude Battery.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The U.S. Department of Labor also has many valuable resources online, including &lt;a href="http://www.mynextmove.org" target="_blank"&gt;mynextmove.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/124135652cropped.jpg" width="529" height="387" alt="Image of the help wanted section of a newspaper with a figure of a person standing in the middle and arrows going in different directions." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468530537</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="674">
        <pagenum>13</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Awareness of opportunity: My Next Move website</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Awareness of opportunity: My Next Move website&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The My Next Move website is an interactive tool for job seekers and students to learn more about their career options. A part of the American Job Center Network, My Next Move has tasks, skills, salary information, and more for over 900 different careers. Users can find careers through keyword search; by browsing industries that employ different types of workers; or through  the powerful O*NET Interest Profiler, an online resource that offers personalized career suggestions based on a person's interests and level of work experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visit the &lt;a href="https://www.mynextmove.org/" target="_blank"&gt;My Next Move website&lt;/a&gt; in English or &lt;a href="https://www.miproximopaso.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Spanish&lt;/a&gt; for further online exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Screen%20Shot%202016-03-03%20at%207.35.09%20PM.png" width="532" height="449" alt="Screenshot from mynextmove.org website." style="border: 1px solid black;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After you have explored the website, click the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; for some instructional activities for the preparation component.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468531464</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="675">
        <pagenum>14</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Preparation: example instructional activities</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Preparation: example instructional activities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the preparation component, example activities include practice completing applications, being interviewed for a job and/or finding job leads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this is a good opportunity to tell adult learners with LD about the value of &lt;b&gt;developing networking skills&lt;/b&gt;. By going out and talking to people who do different kinds of work and learning from them, they are building relationships. This can be extremely difficult for people who are introverted or who may have communication challenges. They will likely need strategies for introducing themselves and expressing interest in learning what other people do. Another useful exercise is to have them talk about their passions and interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/86496361.jpg" width="600" height="400" alt="Photo of an interviewer shaking hands with an interviewee" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457052081</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="676">
        <pagenum>15</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Work history: example instructional activities</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Work history: example instructional activities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;b&gt;work history &lt;/b&gt;example activities almost always include developing a resume. Many resume applications can be done online. You can also practice filling out sample resumes online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another exercise addressing the component of work history involves asking students to list all of the ways they may have acquired skills: their hobbies, working with others, classes in high school through the present (academic and vocational-technical), extracurricular activities, volunteer jobs, paid jobs and so on. What did they learn about themselves through those work experiences? What did they learn about various occupational fields? What did they learn that they can apply to the next steps in their lives? Finding one’s place in the world is often very difficult for people with LD, so emphasizing the importance of learning from every life experience, especially work experience, is extremely valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #993300;"&gt;Continue on to Session 3: Integrated Basic Skills and Career Pathways&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457052235</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>