<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="1582">
  <number>1</number>
  <name>Guiding Question #1</name>
  <summary>&lt;h2 class="Subhead"&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 class="Subhead"&gt;Instructional strategies to support success in the employment process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have an understanding of some common employment-related challenges that adults with LD face, let’s look at some ways educators can help them prepare for some of those challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guiding Question #1 asks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What instructional strategies can instructors use to help adults with LD develop skills that will support success at each phase of the employment process?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin by thinking about employer expectations for today’s workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Identify skills needed for success in the employment process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2006, a coalition of business groups conducted a study of 400 U.S. companies to find out what skills and knowledge employers expect workers to have in today’s economy. They reported their findings in a &lt;a href="http://www.p21.org/storage/documents/FINAL_REPORT_PDF09-29-06.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt; titled, “&lt;i&gt;Are They Really Ready to Work? Employers’ Perspectives on the Basic Knowledge and Applied Skills of New Entrants to the 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; Century U.S. Workforce&lt;/i&gt;.”&lt;a id="_anchor_1" href="#_msocom_1" language="JavaScript" name="_msoanchor_1"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the quiz below, you will be asked to select the skills you think employers identified as essential during the 2006 study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Label"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence>5860,5861,5862,5863</sequence>
  <visible>1</visible>
  <availablefrom>0</availablefrom>
  <availableuntil>0</availableuntil>
  <showavailability>0</showavailability>
  <groupingid>0</groupingid>
</section>