<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="87" moduleid="5866" modulename="book" contextid="19727">
  <book id="87">
    <name>Conclusion</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;conclusion section goes here&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1456963147</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1457395707</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="709">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Review of guiding questions</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Review of guiding questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course has focused our attention on workforce preparation and career development for adults with LD, and the role instructors can play in reinforcing these concepts via academic instruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s wrap up by reviewing our guiding questions.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457395659</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="710">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Review of guiding question #1</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Review of guiding question #1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guiding question number one asked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;"&gt;What instructional strategies can instructors use to help adults with LD develop skills that will support success at each phase of the employment process?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this question we:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reviewed the skills employers identify as essential for workers in today's economy and generated ideas for classroom instructional strategies that would develop these skills;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;examined the four elements of the career development process, as well as the instructor’s role in supporting skill development relating to this process; and&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explored instructional programs and approaches that emphasize integrated basic skills and career pathways - in particular the 16 Career Clusters laid out by the US Department of Labor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457469390</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="711">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Review of guiding question #2</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Review of guiding question #2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our guiding question number two asked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;"&gt;What workforce-related resources are available to students with LD, and how can instructors link these resources to instruction and the learner’s goals?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;___________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to resources already mentioned earlier, we addressed this question through a thorough exploration of the Workforce system or AJC Career Centers. We examined the centers’ partners, customers and services, as well as ideas for assisting students with LD to access these services effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457395856</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="712">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Share your thoughts about the concepts and ideas presented in Workforce Preparation Strategies</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Share your thoughts about the concepts and ideas presented in Workforce Preparation Strategies&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take some time to reflect on what you have learned and your plans for acting on this information by answering the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Of all the concepts and ideas discussed in this course:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which were new to you?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which ideas stood out as most important for you and your practice in supporting adults with LD in your classroom?  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Now, based on your previous reflections:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are some specific strategies from this course that you feel you can readily incorporate into your instruction?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are some workforce-related resources to which you can refer your students?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please share the specific strategies and resources you plan to incorporate into your practice in the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/discussion/online-course-learning-achieve-workforce-preparation-strategies" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Disabilities in Adult Education Group&lt;/a&gt; before moving on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have finished sharing, click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; to review some specific strategies that were presented in this course.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462980613</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="713">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Review ideas presented in Workforce Preparation Strategies</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Review ideas presented in Workforce Preparation Strategies&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, while many answers may apply, some strategies and resources that you might have noted to incorporate into your practice include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice filling out job applications, writing resumes, and answering interview questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading job descriptions or exploring job clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Exploring online work-related resources (state or national).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Math instruction based on specific career goals, such as metric conversions for medical professions.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468534271</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="714">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Participate in the forum discussions</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Participate in the forum discussions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class="Subhead"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal; line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Congratulations on completing Learning to Achieve’s &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i style="font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal; line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Workforce Preparation Strategies&lt;/i&gt;&lt;em style="font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal; line-height: 1.231;"&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal; line-height: 1.231;"&gt; We encourage you to stay involved in the LINCS Community and the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/group/disabilities-adult-education" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Disabilities in Adult Education Group&lt;/a&gt; as you strive to incorporate workforce-related instructional strategies into your classroom instruction and to help adult learners with LD access and use the services of the one-stops. We encourage you to discuss and apply your newly acquired knowledge and learn about others' experiences in helping adults with LD prepare for the workforce.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To access resources from this course, please click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457469478</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="715">
        <pagenum>7</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Complete the evaluation and print your certificate</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Complete the evaluation and print your certificate&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class="Subhead"&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;This concludes the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Workforce Preparation Strategies&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt; course. We would like to thank the individuals and organizations who generously contributed to the design and development of this course:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINCS Regional Professional Development Center, Region 2&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Center for Literacy, Education &amp;amp; Employment at the University of Tennessee, Knoxville&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that we can maintain the quality of our courses, we ask that you take a moment to complete the course evaluation. Your feedback will ensure our courses meet your needs for professional development. Thank you.&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin-bottom: 30px; margin-top: 30px;" class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Access and Print Your Certificate Anytime&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on completing this LINCS Learning to Achieve course, Workforce Preparation Strategies. To obtain your completion certificate, simply close this window and return to the course homepage. You will find a link for the completion certificate under the Course Conclusion and Resources section header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Literacy Information and Communication System (LINCS) Learning to Achieve course was developed by Manhattan Strategy Group, LLC for the U.S. Department of Education, Office of Career, Technical, and Adult Education under Contract No. &lt;i&gt;ED-VAE-14-C-0123.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt; The opinions expressed herein do not necessarily represent the positions or policies of the U.S. Department of Education, and no official endorsement by the U.S. Department of Education should be inferred. This course is in the public domain and may be used without permission.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1469561866</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>