<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="84" moduleid="5863" modulename="book" contextid="19724">
  <book id="84">
    <name>Session 3: Integrated Basic Skills and Career Pathways</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;part 3 of 3 under question 1&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1457052454</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1457052454</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="677">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Emphasizing integrated basic skills and career pathways</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Emphasizing integrated basic skills and career pathways&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s now discuss instructional programs and approaches that emphasize integrated basic skills and career pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As discussed earlier, trends in the current economy have created a need for workers who are able to perform basic literacy tasks and who have strong skills in the areas of communication, problem-solving, and teamwork. It is a monumental task, however, for instructors to both:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;help to meet the needs of employers for skilled technical workers, and&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;provide for the literacy and skills remediation of adult learners who hope to gain and maintain suitable employment and self-sufficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dol.gov/asp/evaluation/jdt/jdt.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Research&lt;/a&gt; indicates that contextual learning shows promise for adult learners. There is also &lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/professional-development/resource-collections/profile-780" target="_blank"&gt;evidence&lt;/a&gt; of a link between literacy and earnings. The &lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/professional-development/resource-collections/profile-730" target="_blank"&gt;Time for the U.S. to Reskill?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://skills.oecd.org/Survey_of_Adult_Skills_US.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; report includes recommendations for increased efforts to link the improvement of basic skills to employability, such as through instructional programs and approaches that emphasize integrated basic skills and career pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/118260809.jpg" width="600" height="400" alt="Photo of a young adult male helping an electrician at an electrical panel." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1460389187</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="678">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Career pathways</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Career pathways&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class="Subhead"&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;While there are a number of definitions of career pathways, a &lt;span style="color: #000000;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ovae/ten-attachment.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;2012 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="nolink"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ovae/ten-attachment.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;joint letter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ovae/ten-attachment.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt; of the U.S. Departments of Education, and Health and Human Services, describes this term as:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt; “&lt;i&gt;…a series of connected education and training strategies and support services that enable individuals to secure industry relevant certification and obtain employment within an occupational area and to advance to higher levels of future education and employment in that area&lt;/i&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May 2016, an &lt;a href="https://s3.amazonaws.com/PCRN/docs/15-0675.CareerPathwaysJointLetterFinal-4-22-2016.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;updated letter&lt;/a&gt; of continued commitment to career pathways systems development was signed by 12 Federal agencies. This letter updates the definition for career pathways to align more closely with the Workforce Innovation and Opportunities Act of 2014 (WIOA), reiterates the six key elements of a career pathways system, and provides updated tools and resources from the expanded group of Federal agency partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act provides a common definition of career pathways for the education and workforce system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term “career pathway” means a combination of rigorous and high-quality education, training, and other services that –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;A.  aligns with the skill needs of industries in the economy of the State or regional &lt;br /&gt;     economy involved;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;B.  prepares an individual to be successful in any of a full range of secondary or &lt;br /&gt;     postsecondary options, including apprenticeships;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;C.  includes counseling to support an individual in achieving the individual’s education &lt;br /&gt;     and career goals;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;D.  includes, as appropriate, education offered concurrently with and in the same &lt;br /&gt;     context as workforce preparation activities and training for a specific &lt;br /&gt;     occupation or occupational cluster;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;E.  organizes education, training, and other services to meet the particular needs of an &lt;br /&gt;     individual in a manner that accelerates the educational and career advancement of &lt;br /&gt;     the individual to the extent practicable;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;F.  enables an individual to attain a secondary school diploma or its recognized &lt;br /&gt;     equivalent, and at least one recognized postsecondary credential; and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;G.  helps an individual enter or advance within a specific occupation or &lt;br /&gt;     occupational cluster. [Section 3(7) of WIOA]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462980178</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="679">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Integrated basic skills</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Integrated basic skills&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this approach, career-technical instructors team with ABE/GED instructors and ESL instructors. Instructors focus on specific occupational skills training (for example: plumbing, mechanics, landscaping, etc.) while concurrently providing literacy education to ABE/GED students, including those who are English Language Learners. Instructors work as a team and the basic skills are taught within the context of a particular career area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/133745221.jpg" width="600" height="400" alt="Photo of three mechanics" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Click the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; to learn about integrating the career pathways approach into your instruction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468531563</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="680">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Objectives of career pathways courses</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Objectives of career pathways courses&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Career pathways are intended to help individuals develop career plans that they can explore and connect to their academic and occupational education and interests. For educators, they provide a means of developing and organizing curricula across 16 different career clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objectives of career pathways course offerings are to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;help students understand and consider career options;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;discover workplaces and their relationship to curricula;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make choices about future education and training; and&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;understand the expectations for achieving career goals, maintain portfolios of progress and achievement, and to become flexible but focused employees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/104399333.jpg" width="600" height="400" alt="Photo of an instructor helping adult learners use computers." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457469036</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="681">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>The LINCS Resource Collection</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;The LINCS Resource Collection&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/professional-development/resource-collection/search-resources?keys=&amp;amp;field_rcis_topic_areas_value%5B%5D=Career+Pathways" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Resource Collection&lt;/a&gt; includes a large library of online instructional materials and resources related to work readiness, workforce education and career pathways for adult learners in ABE/GED programs. You may also explore other resources housed on LINCS specific to &lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/programs/acp" target="_blank"&gt;Adult Career Pathways&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Screen%20Shot%202016-03-04%20at%2012.54.30%20PM.png" width="514" height="491" alt="Screenshot of the LINCS Resource Collection web page." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468531831</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="682">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Career clusters</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Career clusters&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Labor has laid out guidelines to group occupations into career clusters based on broad industry commonalities. Career clusters can help prepare learners for higher education and careers by providing them with relevant contexts for learning and linking what they learned in school to the knowledge and skills needed for a successful career. Connecting education to future career goals can help motivate learners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many resources are organized according to these career clusters or occupational categories that define the skills and knowledge needed to work in particular industries. These are often good resources to use when developing instructional material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s examine some career clusters in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457114442</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="683">
        <pagenum>7</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>16 Career clusters</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;16 Career clusters&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 16 Career Clusters are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agriculture, Food, and Natural Resources;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Architecture and Construction;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arts, AV Technology, and Communication;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business Management and Administration;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education and Training;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finance;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government and Public Administration;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health Science;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hospitality and Tourism;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Human Services;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Technology;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Law, Public Safety, Corrections, and Security;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manufacturing;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marketing, Sales, and Service;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Science, Engineering, Information Technology; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transportation, Distribution, and Logistics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/CareerClusters_Graphic.jpg" width="560" height="305" alt="graphic table of the 16 career clusters" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1460389552</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="684">
        <pagenum>8</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Other occupational groupings</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Other occupational groupings&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Labor does not limit itself, however, to just the 16 career clusters framework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other currently used occupational groupings include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bright Outlook – occupations that are expected to grow rapidly in the next several years, will have large numbers of job openings, or are new and emerging occupations.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Green Jobs – occupations connected to or affected by environmentally conscious industry efforts and economic sectors.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Job Families – groups of occupations based upon work performed, skills, education, training, and credentials.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Industry groups – broad groups of businesses or organizations with similar activities, products, or services.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;STEM occupations – occupations that require education in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) disciplines.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the preferred grouping, however, the &lt;a href="https://www.mynextmove.org/" target="_blank"&gt;mynextmove.org&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.onetonline.org/" target="_blank"&gt;O-NET OnLine&lt;/a&gt; resources can assist learners to explore job possibilities and create career plans based on their needs and interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Screen%20Shot_MyNextMove.png" width="531" height="449" alt="Screenshot of the My Next Move website." style="border: 1px solid black;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468531877</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="685">
        <pagenum>9</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Integrating the career pathways approach</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Integrating the career pathways approach&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we ask you to consider for a moment, how could you integrate the career pathways approach into your work with adult learners with LD? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have generated one or more ideas, click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; for some suggestions you might want to consider.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1457122832</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="686">
        <pagenum>10</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Ideas for integrating the career pathways approach</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Ideas for integrating the career pathways approach&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideas for incorporating the career pathways approach into instruction for adults with LD will vary, but here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instructors can help students to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;link interests and aptitudes to specific career areas; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explore the types of skills and training needed for certain careers; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;create an educational plan for a particular career pathway.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468533012</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="687">
        <pagenum>11</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Share your thoughts and ideas in the discussion forum</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Share your thoughts and ideas in the discussion forum&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve discussed instructional strategies instructors can use to help adults with LD develop skills that will support success at each phase of the employment process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a few moments to consider the examples presented. Then answer the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have you used any of the ideas presented in your classroom instruction? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;What other strategies, activities, and methods have you used to help adults with LD develop skills that will support success at each phase of the employment process?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Which ones seem to be the most effective?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;How do you know?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please share your reflections and ideas, and read other teachers’ responses in the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/discussion/online-course-learning-achieve-workforce-preparation-strategies" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Disabilities in Adult Education Group&lt;/a&gt; before moving on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000;"&gt;When you have finished posting your ideas, click the &lt;strong&gt;up arrow&lt;/strong&gt; to return to the course home page and expand the Guiding Question #2 header bar.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468533036</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>